Application Frameworks-LAB1

Objective: Teach set of basic concepts in JavaScript programming language. Prerequisites: Student should have basic JavaScript knowledge. 
 
1. Create a function as a variable (function expression) that prints ‘Hello World’ to console and another function which accepts a variable. The argument passed to the second function should be executed as a function inside the body. Call the second function passing the first function as the argument. Check the output. 
 
 
2. Use curly brackets to create JSON like JavaScript object and add properties and functions to the object. 
 
3. Understand the ‘this’ keyword in JavaScript. 
 
● Declare a global variable named vehicleName in the window object 
● Declare a method named printVehicleName to print out the vehicle name 
● Declare an object named Vehicle(using object literal notation) which have a variable called vehicleName and declare a function named getVehicleName and assign it with the printVehicleName  
● Execute the printVehicleName function and the getVehicleName functions to see the results 
● Correct the getVehicleName to print out the global variable vehicleName using the this keyword 
 
4. Create a separate function using JavaScript closure which accepts the tax percentage and returns a function which accepts the amount and returns the amount after adding tax percentage. Try adding tax percentage to ‘this’ object and check if it works. 
 
5. Write a function to call GitHub API (https://api.github.com/users) and get users and return the users to the caller. 